MOSCOW, RUSSIA
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN ON POLICE RADIO)
DR. HIRSCH: Send him in.
DR. HIRSCH: Will you commit to this program?
I can't.
Will you commit to this program?
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
ABBOTT: There's no place it won't catch up to you. It's how every story ends.
It's what you are, Jason, a killer.
You always will be.
Go ahead. Go on. Go on! Do it! Do it!
BOURNE: She wouldn't want me to.
That's the only reason you're alive.
KRAMER: Who is "she"?
Marie Kreutz, his girlfriend.
She was killed in India.
Director of Operations Ward Abbott arranged it.
So we have a dirty section chief who kills Bourne's girl.
Bourne comes back for revenge, tapes Abbott's confession
and Abbott commits suicide.
Now Bourne's gunning for us.
You couldn't make this stuff up.
Bourne's last confirmed location was Moscow, six weeks ago.
Right. Sir.
He's on the run. He's dangerous.
Well, sir, with respect, I think something else could be going on here.
What? What's he after?
The reason Bourne went to Moscow was to see the daughter of his first target.
What's your point, Pam?
Maybe he was retracing his steps.
He's looking for something. Something in his past.
Maybe he hasn't found it yet and we need to know what it is.
Are you telling me he's not a threat to this agency?
I think if he wanted to hurt us, he could have sent the tape to CNN.
Maybe he still will.
My number one rule is hope for the best, plan for the worst.
As far as I'm concerned, Bourne is still a serious threat until proven otherwise.
Let's keep looking.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
ROSS: This one's three years ago. They had half of Interpol after him.
Turned up in Naples, Berlin, Moscow...
Disappeared again.
The girl that he was on the run with.
Marie Kreutz. She was found dead in a river halfway round the world.
She'd been shot in the head.
What connects the dots?
Turn off the tape recorder.
Where's my sister?
Why don't you sit down?
Where is she?
She's dead.
She was killed.
I'm sorry.
I knew this could end this way.
It was always gonna end this way. I didn't believe that.
And how did she die?
She was shot.
We were together in India.
He came for me.
You killed him?
Yes.
And now what?
Someone started all of this and I'm gonna find them.
Hey. It's me.
Yeah. He knows the whole story.
Bourne's just the tip of the iceberg.
Have you heard of an Operation Black briar?
I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up. I'll see you first thing.
WOMAN: Scanning. Go Sat 21. I have a hit on ECHELON. Black briar.
I repeat, Black briar.
Looks like it's coming from a European signal.
NSA, please confirm your receipt.
WOMAN: I'll bring up the frequency and the coordinates
...intercept of our principal...
Sir! What you got?
We intercepted a call in London. Keyword, "Black briar."
Okay, send it to New York right away.
Track the phone? Registered to a London reporter named Simon Ross.
Works at the Guardian newspaper.
You're tracking him? Sir. Yeah.
Thanks, Mike.
We have a survey team covering him at work
and a sneak and peek's on their way to his apartment.
Well, who talked to him? How did he find out about Black briar?
I don't know. We pulled his background
and ran a cross-check on any known anomalies.
We've come up with nothing. But I think if we follow Ross, we're gonna be able...
Ray, Ross is easy. We want the source.
ROSS: Have you heard of an Operation Black briar?
MAN: You have details?
ROSS: I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up.
I'll see you first thing.
Is that all? Yeah.
I want rendition protocols and put the asset on standby, just in case.
People, listen up! This is a full priority situation.
Jimmy, give me Ross' profile on one. Yes, sir.
Our target is a British national, Simon Ross. A reporter.
I want all his phones, his Blackberry, his apartment, his car,
bank accounts, credit cards, travel patterns.
I want to know what he's gonna think before he does.
Every dirty little secret he has.
And most of all, we want the name and real-time location of his source.
This is NSA priority level four. Any questions?
All right, let's get to it.
What?
DR. HIRSCH: Will you commit to this program?
I can't.
Copy that. Mr. Wills, the subject is entering his office.
Give me some eyeballs on the street.
Where's my picture, please? Coming online.
Online now.
WILLS: Jimmy, how you doing with the phone line?
JIMMY: Yeah, we have an office line. We're working on his cell.
WILLS: How long? An hour, sir.
That's too long.
So how do we know he's not spinning for someone?
There was more. He was scared.
Scared about what? Black briar.
Sorry. Call for you. ROSS: Who is it?
Won't give his name.
Excuse me.
He's on my line. Thanks.
Simon Ross. MAN: Camera three, screen.
Why aren't we hearing this?
Jimmy? That's a hard line, Jimmy. Why don't we have it?
JIMMY: We have his line, sir, but he's not on it. He's using a different phone.
BOURNE: I've been reading your stories.
Who is this? This is Jason Bourne.
Waterloo Station. South entrance. Thirty minutes. Come alone.
WILLS: Get me audio as soon as you can, Ted.
MAN: Street teams Alpha, Bravo.
WILLS: Okay, guys, let's work it. Come on.
Where's he going?
Okay, he is on the move. Give me eyeballs on the street. Let's go.
MOBILE ONE: Subject exiting the building.
WILLS: All right, everyone, let's find out where he's going.
BRIAN: Mobile One, I need audio.
Audio engaged.
Mobile One should have him. Get Mobile One on it. Let me know when you hear it.
ROSS: Hi. Waterloo Station, south entrance.
Mr. Wills. VOSEN: Where's he going?
Destination is Waterloo Station.
Okay, Waterloo Station. Give me eyes at Waterloo. Put everyone in play.
WILLS: Let's activate the asset. MAN: Mobilize Tracker Three.
Are we at the bridge yet? WOMAN: Not yet, sir.
Okay, Mobile Three, tell them to stay back. Sir.
Please maintain visual contact.
Prepaid phone.
Here you go.
BRIAN: Mobile One, give me the subject's current location.
Copy that.
Sir, the subject is arriving at the south entrance of Waterloo Station.
MAN: Give me that on five and seven as well.
Jimmy, I need that phone.
BOURNE: I want you to listen very carefully to what I'm about to tell you.
What the hell's going on?
Ten o'clock, to your left, across the street, there's a silver Chrysler Voyager.
There's a surveillance team inside.
Directly across the street, twelve noon,
there's a man on the second story, static post. He's watching you.
Now, there's a bus stop 50 meters to your left. I want you to walk towards it.
WILLS: Jimmy, I need that phone! I need it yesterday.
He's on the move. He's on the move.
JIMMY: That's not his phone, sir. Say again?
That's not his phone, sir. What do you mean that's not his phone?
Where the hell did he get another phone?
Well, no, you just have to...
BRIAN: Grab Team B, stand by.
Grab Team B. We're in position.
All right, there's a man in a blue hooded sweatshirt.
He's talking on a phone. Walk directly to him and stop.
WILLS: Jimmy, we need the call. I need that cell phone.
BRIAN: Do not let him get out of sight.
All right, turn around.
Okay, who's the guy in the blue hood?
Is that his contact?
All right, there's a bus coming. It'll be there in ten seconds.
When it stops, I want you to walk directly to your left.
There's an overpass. Go up the stairs. Stop at the newsstand.
You'll get further instructions. Okay. Okay.
Get ready to move.
Watch that bus. Watch that bus. WILLS: What? All right, what's going on?
Somebody tell me. We lost the feed. Grab Team B. Intercept the contact and stay with Ross.
Mobile One. Target's on the move.
Okay, he's on the move. Do not lose Ross.
Blue hood! Down! Now!
WOMAN: Go! Let's go.
Oh, shit.
What the hell was that?
MAN: Sir, we've lost all communication with Mobile One.
To the right! Heading west. Let us know when you get a visual!
What was the last known position, please?
JIMMY: On the walkway, heading towards the concourse, sir.
It's a surveillance nightmare. It's the busiest terminal in London.
Give me all of CCTV's eyes. WOMAN: On it, sir.
MAN: Sir, asset's on scene.
Who's your source?
What's his name? What's your source's name?
Look, what's going on? Why are these people after me?
Because you found something.
You talked to someone inside Tread stone.
Someone who was there at the beginning. Who is it?
You know I can't tell you that.
You have no idea what you're into here. These people will kill you, if they have to.
Was it Black briar? Is that what this is?
What's Black briar?
Tread stone upgrade. My source told me it all started with you.
He said that you were square one, the dirty little secret.
He said he knows who you are.
All right, we have to move.
Answer your phone.
Coming online. MAN: You got visual?
Where the hell is he, people?
Do exactly as I say. I need you to move up to your right.
First escalator on the right.
Tie your shoe. Tie your shoe right now. Tie your shoe.
Wait.
I'm gonna walk by you. I want you to move along the far wall
to your left in four, three, two, one.
Stand up.
That's it.
Where the hell is he?
We cannot afford to lose this guy, people.
All right, that line you're on is good. Stay on that line. Stay on that line.
I've gotta go and pick up the kids. Can you go and get the shopping done?
Oh, the bin man, I think he's one of them.
The garbage man? Negative.
Oh, Jesus. Jesus! He's reaching for something.
Oh, God, he's got a gun. BOURNE: Stay on the line.
He's got a gun. He's got a gun. Stay on the line you're on. Do not deviate.
Okay, there he is! Here he goes. Grab Team A. Go!
He's still talking to somebody.
He's getting instructions. Jimmy, get me the conversation. Mobile Two, I want...Come on, lock the box.
Lock the box. Move in, Grab Team C.
Hurry, Ross. We gotta move.
Okay, move through this crowd. Move through this crowd.
Get undercover right now. Move through this crowd.
Get in the store. There's someone on your tail. Get in the store.
You're gonna proceed out the east exit. That's to your right as you come into the store.
Head into the liquor store in front of you.
Go into the back and lock the door.
Mobile Four is down.
This guy's got help. Tell me when the asset's in the nest.
Get me a feed in there!
I want Grab Team C in there. Tell me what's going on.
Team Four is mobile.
Jesus Christ.
That's Jason Bourne.
He's picking us apart. Do you think he's the source?
He's gotta be.
Block all the exits. Give the asset a green light.
Take them both out.
Stay there.
I'm gonna get us out of here. You gotta do exactly what I say.
Listen to me! This isn't some story in a newspaper.
This is real. You understand me?
Call all agents back.
Give Bourne's location at the back of the store to the asset.
Yes, sir.
Kill the cameras.
ROSS: Bourne. Wait. Something's not right.
I can see the entrance from here. If I go now, I can make it.
Bourne?
Just stay where you are.
ROSS: I don't think we should wait!
I think someone's coming.
I'm going for it. No, no, no, no, no!
We have a situation.
Director Kramer would like to see you.
We need to get those warrants... He said it's urgent.
REPORTER: What the police will tell me is that they believe the victim is 35-year-old
Simon Ross, a well-known journalist based here in London with the Guardian newspaper.
It appears that he was gunned down
right in the middle of the Waterloo Station concourse
around 3:45 this afternoon in full view of hundreds of commuters.
Over the years, he's uncovered a lot of
unsavory stories about terror
that have upset certain Western governments and...
Hi, how are you? Right over there?
All right.
Good morning, sir. Can I take your order? Yes.
I'll have the Heart-Healthy omelet with goat cheese and peppers, please.
Anything for you, ma'am? Just coffee, please.
Are you sure? I'm buying. I'm good.
So, when the Director called and it was suggested that we bring you on...
Suggested? You sure it was just a suggestion?
You know, it's funny how different things look depending on where you sit, right?
I look at this as a favor for you, Pam,
giving you an opportunity to complete some unfinished business.
Meaning?
Bourne. He's here. He's a threat.
And we both want the same thing.
But we both go about it in two very different ways.
The past is past, Pam. All right?
We were careless in Stockholm.
So what was Waterloo? Just careless again?
We had a leak. A serious national security situation.
Bourne showed up on our surveillance and we had very little time to react.
And a reporter got killed.
Bourne saw us coming. The question is what was he doing there?
No, the real question is how you managed
to get into a firefight at a public train station.
You know as well as I do decisions made in real time are never perfect.
Don't second-guess an operation from an armchair.
I'll see you at the office.
Enjoy your egg whites.
VOSEN: People!
This is Pamela Landy and her associate, Tom Cronin.
She's gonna be quarterbacking the search effort.
Say your names. State your specs, please.
Well, let's do names later, okay? What's Bourne's last fixed position?
JIMMY: London, 1200 Zulu.
Status. What is he? Armed? Wounded?
JIMMY: Alive, mobile and unknown.
Do we have an ECHELON package? WOMAN: Yes.
Why isn't it on? We were waiting.
Waiting? For what? What... Listen,
people, do you have any idea who you're dealing with?
This is Jason Bourne.
You are nine hours behind the toughest target you have ever tracked.
Now, I want everyone to sit down, strap in and turn on all you've got.
That would mean now!
Thank you.
Give me a team deployment plan.
I want everything you got on Ross on screen one.
(CALLING BELL SOUNDING)
BRIAN: Sir, I think we have something.
We just hacked Ross' e-mail account at the Guardian.
Found a round-trip ticket to Turin, Italy, yesterday.
0800 arrival, 1205 departure.
I think we can be pretty certain that Bourne's not your source, then.
How?
Ross's call to his editor where he said he'd just met the source
took place just after his Turin flight landed.
He met his source in Turin. So?
What? So, what? Bourne met Ross in Turin for breakfast
and then at noon the same day Bourne calls Ross to demand a meet at Waterloo?
Maybe they were even on the same flight.
Pull up everything you've got.
Cross-check the secure cell phone usage of everyone with SCI clearance
against all calls going in and out of Turin, Italy, the morning Ross was there.
This guy you're after is a CIA operative with clearance above top secret.
He's committing treason by talking to Ross.
Do you really think while doing that
he's gonna use a cell phone that he knows we can track?
Zero results on the cross-check. So, you got any better ideas?
Yeah, look at all the people whose cell phones were switched off
the entire period Ross was in Turin.
I mean, if your people are on their phones as much as mine,
the list should be pretty small.
Three names. Tom Brewster, Jack Boulin and Neal Daniels.
Okay, now check everything in Ross' apartment against those names.
Check for common patterns. Look for anything that indicates who Ross met.
Pull up his socials. Pull it up.
See those documents? CRONIN: Break it.
Over here. What is that?
All right. Right there. Initials.
Pull that up. Bring that up on main.
Neal Daniels.
He's station chief in Madrid, isn't he? Yeah.
All right, call the RSO at the embassy.
Have them take Daniels into custody, if he is there.
Anna, get grab teams to the Calle Norte safe house.
Send them in heavy. Tell them we'll assist with the entry.
Heavy? Daniels isn't really that much of a... I'm worried about Bourne.
If he is not the source,
then he is after the source, the same as we are.
ETA, Team Two. Three minutes to destination, sir.
DR. HIRSCH: Your mission will save American lives.
Really give yourself to this program.
I can't.
DR. HIRSCH: You can.
Sir, they're at the front door.
Five seconds. Put it up live.
We're in.
The alarm's down.
That's gotta be Bourne.
The safe is empty. Shit.
Looks like he left in a hurry.
Track Daniels' passports. Stand by.
(WHISPERING) Hammond.
God damn it! Get a backup team in there!
Get me a secure line in there. Get the second team over there now!
What are you doing here?
I was posted here after Berlin.
Where's Daniels?
Where is he?
Who is this?
This is Nicky Parsons.
She was Tread stone. Logistics.
She was with us when we hunted Bourne in Berlin.
Nicky, I need to do an ID challenge.
Code in, Sparrow.
Response, Everest.
Nicky, this is Noah Vosen. How long have you been on-site?
I just walked in.
We have two officers on-site. Are you in contact with them?
They're down. Unconscious but alive.
Any sign of Neal Daniels? No.
Nicky, this is Pam Landy.
We have reason to believe there's a connection between Neal Daniels and Jason Bourne.
Bourne? You're still looking for Bourne? I thought that case was closed.
No, some people are convinced he's still a threat.
I disagree, but to find out I need to talk to him.
Hold on, Nicky.
What the hell are you doing? I'm trying to send him a message.
You don't think Bourne is a threat? He just took out two more of my men.
The only way this has a happy ending, Noah,
is if we bring him in alive.
He is going after Daniels.
He wants revenge, Pam, and the only realistic way
to end this is to eliminate the threat.
How long until backup?
Nicky, I need you to stay put and secure the premises.
Backup will be arriving in approximately one hour. Do you copy?
NICKY: Copy, sir. (PHONE BEEPING)
How long do I have? Three minutes.
My car's outside.
I know where Daniels is.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Come on.
Two minutes to destination, sir. WILLS: Grab Teams A and B...
Where was Daniels headed?
At 8:00 this morning, he wired $100,000 to a bank account in Tangier.
Right, that's 300 miles away. If we hurry, we can make the morning ferry.
Where are you parked?
To the right, 20 meters, north side of the street.
They're coming. Keep moving.
MAN: Two subjects seen exiting safe house.
What the hell is this?
MAN: Wait, wait, wait! No, no, no!
What the hell just happened?
We've lost visual contact with the subjects, sir. Christ!
Issue a standing kill order on Jason Bourne, effective immediately.
Send out a system one alert to all Spanish contacts. I want all air and ground border exits locked down.
What's going on?
What's Daniels got?
What's Operation Black briar?
Do you want to tell me, or should I call Kramer and ask him?
For Christ's sake, Pam, we're in the middle of an operation.
Bullshit.
You want Jason Bourne,
level with me.
Operation Black briar started as an NEAT surveillance program.
And what is it now?
It is now the umbrella program for all our black ops.
Full envelope intrusion, rendition, experimental interrogation
is all run out of this office.
We are the sharp end of the stick now, Pam.
Lethal action?
If we have to, sure.
That's what makes us special. No more red tape.
No more getting the bad guys caught in our sights,
then watching them escape
while we wait for someone in Washington to issue the order.
Oh, come on.
You've seen the raw intel, Pam. You know how real the danger is.
We need these programs now.
What's the connection to Daniels?
He ran all of our operations in Southern Europe and North Africa,
so he has everything.
Names, dates, ghost sites, who's cooperating with us abroad.
Every operation.
You want that stuff in Bourne's hands, out on the market to the highest bidder?
I don't think so.
Bourne's not after money. He's after Daniels for a reason.
Well, what does it matter what Bourne is after?
When we find Daniels, and, believe me, we'll find him,
if you're right,
we get Bourne, too.
Why did you come back?
Why are you looking for Daniels?
Do you know who that is?
That's Daniels.
I don't know who that is. Who is he?
He was there at the beginning.
I remember meeting him.
The first day.
Daniels brought me to him.
That's where it all started for me.
Something happened to me and I need to know what it was
or I'll never be free of this.
Daniels said the training was experimental.
Behavior modification.
They had to break down the agents before they became operational.
He said you were the first one.
Why are you helping me?
It was difficult for me
with you.
You really don't remember anything.
No.
We have to move.
Sir? Mr. Wills? You're gonna want to look at this.
WILLS: He's in Tangier.
Noah Vosen.
We have found Daniels.
They've just tracked Daniels' passport to a hotel in Tangier.
They're holding up a bank transfer he made to keep him in place
while they bring an asset up from Casablanca.
They're gonna take him out.
Yeah. WOMAN: It's Pam Landy. She says it's urgent.
Tell her I'm unavailable. Yes, sir.
BRIAN: Sir, asset has arrived at the airport.
Give me the subject's location.
MAN: Subject is now on foot and entering Hotel Velasquez.
Hotel is 2.2 kilometers from the bank.
All right, get an elevation and a floor plan, tic-tac-toe.
Locate the room.
Give the asset subject location and the route between the subject's hotel and the bank.
VOSEN: Do we have that room yet? MAN: Yes, sir. It's room 117.
All right, get a hold of the hotel trunk line.
Run all calls through here with an ISO on room 117.
His location's being blocked by the firewall.
No, they found Daniels. They know where he is.
They'll get one of the operatives to terminate him.
Find out who.
NICKY: Desh.
Tell him you're gonna meet him and you have a new phone for him.
If you stop Desh, they'll just get someone else.
No, we're not gonna stop him, we're gonna follow him.
He'll take us right to Daniels.
Sir, the asset is deviating off course.
Let it play.
Asset unscheduled stop.
Sir, asset is on the move en route to subject.
WILLS: Sir, we have an unauthorized breach.
Someone with active system knowledge penetrated our protocol.
Instructions were sent to the asset at 1411 local time.
Trace is confirmed and valid. It came from a computer belonging to Nicky Parsons.
Where did the course deviation occur?
South to Rue de Belgique, stationary Place de France.
That's where Parsons is.
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after her.
MAN: Yes, sir.
We find Parsons, we find Bourne.
Noah, what are you doing?
Not now. I wanna know what's going on.
I said not now!
What basis are you continuing this operation on?
On the basis that Nicky Parsons has compromised a covert operation.
She is up to her neck in this! This is about Daniels, not Nicky!
She has betrayed us. You don't know the circumstances, Noah.
She's in league with Jason Bourne, for Christ's sakes!
You do not have the authority to kill her!
Oh, yes, I do. And you had better get on board.
Noah, she's one of us.
You start down this path, where does it end?
It ends when we've won.
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after them.
Yes, sir. MAN 1: Okay, come on. MAN 2: Stand by...
Two minutes, sir. Two minutes. Tell the bank to release the funds.
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
He's on the move.
On it, sir.
MAN 1: Two hundred meters. MAN 2: Okay, come on, I want to lay in some preliminary tracking.
Stop!
(BEEPING)
Code it in. We need to be dead.
Sir? Asset confirms both targets are down.
I want to be sure about this.
Ask the station chief from Rabat to confirm the deaths
and do a sub-rosa collection of the bodies. I want to tie this thing off completely.
And keep an eye on Landy.
VOSEN: Bourne and Nicky Parsons are dead.
You sure about that?
Our station chief in Rabat is confirming.
I can't afford to have this come back to me.
Don't worry. You're protected.
Just remember why we put Landy there.
If Black briar goes south, we'll roll it up, hang it around her neck and start over.
I can see their faces.
Everyone I ever killed.
I just don't know their names.
Marie used to try to
help me remember the names.
I've tried to apologize for... For what I've done.
For what I am.
None of it makes it any better.
They're gonna come for you again.
You're gonna have to run now.
We should go.
It gets easier.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Station chief in Rabat just called.
They found a body.
Bourne? Desh.
Pam. You need to see this.
A passport for Gilberto de Piento just cleared immigration.
It's an early Tread stone identity registered to Jason Bourne,
but he never used it, and it never went to the grid.
Bourne's alive.
They don't know?
Well, if they knew, Vosen wouldn't be in his office right now.
It's a hell of a risk.
Maybe Bourne wants us to know.
Just like Naples. Maybe he's communicating.
Maybe he's trying to communicate with you.
Then we should communicate back.
I think I know what Bourne's looking for.
MAN ON PA: Gilberto de Piento. Gilberto de Piento.
Your party is waiting for you.
Pamela Landy.
I hear you're still looking for me.
Bourne?
What do you want? (TELEPHONE BEEPING)
Yeah? WILLS O VER INTERCOM: Better get in here. We got a situation.
I...
I wanted to thank you for the tape.
LAND Y ON SPEAKER: It's all tied off. It's over.
I guess I owe you an apology.
Is that official?
No. Off the record. You know how it is.
You tracing this? MAN: Fifty seconds to trace.
Goodbye. Wait. Wait.
David Webb. That's your real name.
You were born 4/15/71 in Nixa, Missouri.
Why don't you come in and we'll talk about it?
Something is very wrong here.
Bourne?
Get some rest, Pam.
You look tired.
He's looking right at her.
People, listen up!
This is a national security emergency. We have an imminent threat.
I'm going out there.
If I show myself, he'll find me.
Jason Bourne is alive and is at large in New York City,
and, we believe, within 1,000 yards of this building.
I want an immediate 12-block lockdown of the area.
Send a flash message to Langley. Prep for local backup assistance.
Landy just left the building! Stay with her phone.
She's using her cell. There's an incoming text.
Get it. MAN: Working on it, sir.
How many do we have on Landy? Six men. More on the way.
I've got it, sir! Coming up on the screen now.
Anybody not on Landy goes directly to Tudor City.
Get the vehicles. We're going mobile.
Team Two. Team Two. All teams, call in.
178th.
There's only one way out of there. Why would he do that?
He's trapping himself.
It's a bad place to meet. It's too exposed.
He wouldn't have chosen it if he didn't have a reason.
Subject is en route.
MAN: Roof 43, let me know when you have visual.
Roof 43, standing by.
Standing by.
Okay, folks, here we go. Box 200 meters.
Visual on leader.
43 ground in position.
As soon as you have eyes on Landy, I wanna know.
Okay, here we go.
Copy that. I see her.
Any sign of Bourne?
MAN: Negative.
MAN 2: No sign of target.
Noah Vosen.
This is Jason Bourne.
I was wondering when you were going to make this call.
How did you get this number?
You didn't actually think I was coming to Tudor City, did you?
No, I guess not.
But if it's me you want to talk to, perhaps we can arrange a meet.
Where are you now?
I'm sitting in my office.
I doubt that.
And why would you doubt that?
If you were in your office right now,
we'd be having this conversation face to face.
(ON RECORDER) Noah Vosen.
This is a code ten abort.
I want everyone back in the vehicles. This is a code ten abort.
MAN: Let's go! Let's go!
Yeah? Wills, check my office. (PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Damn it! VOSEN: What's going on?
We need building security up here.
He's got everything. God damn it!
All right, set a four-block perimeter around the building.
MAN: Somebody give me a visual.
I want the entire building searched.
Every room, every hallway, every closet, every goddamn air duct.
You understand? I want him found!
What just happened?
Bourne just broke into CRI. He got into Vosen's safe.
Where to?
415 East 71st Street.
Four-fifteen-seventy-one? Jesus, Pam.
Target in sight.
North on Eighth.
He's headed east in the Port Authority.
All agents have shoot-on-sight authorization.
Sir, he drove off the roof. What?
He drove off the roof!
He's on foot. He's running.
Police! Freeze! Put your hands in the air!
Call for backup!
Sir, sir, take a look at this! Bourne's birthday, sir.
What about it? Check that out.
Sir, Landy told Bourne that his birthday was 4l15l71.
（ 9/13/70 ）
Oh, my God. It's a code.
Everything stops. Everything stops! Listen up!
4l15l71. New assignment, numbers.
What does it mean? Give me encryption codes!
Sir, if you plug them in as variables of longitude and latitude
you get Cameroon.
41571 is the zip code for Varney, Kentucky.
What date did she give him? WILLS: 4/15/71.
I don't believe it.
SRD is at 415 East 71st Street.
She just gave him the training facility. Oh, Christ.
Bring all the teams in behind us.
Hurry up! Somebody call 911!
Help him!
WILLS: The asset lost Bourne. We lost him.
Hello? Albert, it's Vosen.
Bourne knows everything and he's on his way to you right now.
He's coming home, Noah.
How long do I have? I don't know.
Just get the hell out of there.
No, I'm gonna stay.
He'll head for the training wing. That's what he knows.
I'll keep him in play till you get there.
They'll kill you for giving me this.
4l15l71 isn't much of a code.
My guess is Vosen is on his way already.
Why'd you do it?
Because this isn't what I signed up for, what they did to you, Black briar.
This isn't us.
Then do something about it. Everything you need is in there.
Everything.
David. Why don't you come in with me?
It'll be better if we do this together. No.
This is where it started for me. This is where it ends.
That's Landy.
All right, lock this building down. Set a secure perimeter of one block.
Hello. This is Pamela Landy. I have to send a classified document.
Get a team to SRD after Bourne.
And put someone in every public area of this hospital.
Okay. Elevator shafts, service entrances, go!
Damn it! South bay! Go!
Gentlemen, this is a priority one situation! You will give us your full cooperation.
Give me playback for the entire building for the last three minutes.
Yes, sir.
Move! Move!
This one, here! Where is this? First floor.
I'll take Landy on my own.
You better get yourself a good lawyer.
DR. HIRSCH: A republic lives on the knife's edge.
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
You may not even remember who he was.
You know why we're treating you like this?
Hello, Jason. (GUN COCKING)
I believe you've been having some problems.
Put the gun down.
I wouldn't be here if I didn't want to talk.
I've spent three years running.
Three years trying to find out who I am.
You've still not got it all back, have you?
Still not filled in the pieces. It was always you.
I'm unarmed, Jason.
Why me? Why did you pick me?
Your really don't remember, do you?
We didn't pick you. You picked us.
You volunteered.
Right here.
Even after you were warned.
(LOCK CLICKING)
Captain Webb.
Good morning, Captain.
You came in here.
You didn't even blink, Jason.
You just handed me these.
DR. HIRSCH: Has everything been explained to you?
Yes, sir.
You said you wanted to serve.
Your missions will save American lives. WEBB: I understand, sir.
You said I'd be saving American lives.
You were.
I was killing for you. For them.
You knew exactly what it meant for you if you chose to stay.
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
I'll be whoever you need me to be, sir.
You can't outrun what you did, Jason.
You made yourself into who you are.
Eventually you're gonna have to face the fact
you chose right here to become Jason Bourne.
DR. HIRSCH: You haven't slept for a long time.
Have you made a decision?
This can't go on.
You have to decide.
Who is he? We've been through that.
What did he do?
It doesn't matter.
You came to us.
You volunteered.
You said you'd do anything it takes to
save American lives.
You're not a liar, are you?
Or too weak
to see this through?
This is it.
Let go of David Webb.
Really give yourself to this program.
You're no longer
David Webb.
From now on, you'll be known as Jason Bourne.
Welcome to the program.
Do you remember now?
I remember.
I remember everything.
I'm no longer Jason Bourne.
So now you're gonna kill me.
No.
You don't deserve the star they'd give you on the wall at Langley.
MAN: He's headed for the roof!
Why didn't you take the shot?
Do you even know why you're supposed to kill me?
Look at us.
Look at what they make you give.
Good morning, senators.
If I may, I'd like to begin by making a statement for the record.
The file indicates that Ezra Kramer authorized six illegal...
REPORTER ON TV: The President convened an emergency cabinet meeting today
to discuss the growing scandal over an alleged government assassination program,
code-named Black briar.
CIA Director Ezra Kramer
is under criminal investigation
for authorizing the program,
which in several cases may have even targeted US citizens.
Two agency officials have already been arrested.
Dr. Albert Hirsch, the alleged mastermind of Black briar program
and CIA Deputy Director Noah Vosen, the program's operational chief.
Meanwhile, mystery surrounds the fate of David Webb, also known as Jason Bourne, the source
behind the exposure of the Black briar program.
It's been reported that Webb was shot and fell from a Manhattan rooftop
into the East River ten stories below.
However, after a three-day search, Webb's body has yet to be found. (TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)